<u>jeff.j.sweeney@gmail.com</u> <u>jeffsweeney.me</u>

Github: @codegoblins

# **Skills**

#### Javascript & ES 2015

On the web side, I have extensive experience with AngularJS 1.x and D3 3.x. As for the backend, I have written several small projects in NodeJS, using Express 4 for writing web services. In my spare time, I have been using React in personal projects.

#### Sass & CSS

I write rich, reusable web components with Angular/React and Sass. I am comfortable working in any design language, and I love to experiment. I have designed components for seamless visual integration with Material Design, Metro, and vanilla Bootstrap.

### **Modern Web Development Toolchain**

I work with npm and bower to manage project dependencies, and write build tasks using Gulp and Webpack. View the source of my personal site to check out some example project setup code, or fork my base repo if you want to easily reuse this setup.

## **Containerization & Docker**

I have extensive experience containerizing applications for running on a Kubernetes deployment. I am comfortable deploying a service from start to finish on any docker setup.

#### **Application Lifecycle and Infrastructure**

I have spent 4 years working in eBay's Cloud Infrastructure team supporting developers site-wide, so I have a good grasp on the infrastructure that powers modern web services.

#### **Unix Environments**

I work great with a shell (preferably zsh), and I can apt-get, curl, and pipe like a pro.

## **General Software Development**

I was classically trained with Java and C, and I have worked with some Golang in my time in Kubernetes-land.

# **Work Experience**

#### Software Engineer (Frontend) — eBay (January 2014-present)

I currently work as a frontend engineer embedded on the Cloud Engineering team at eBay. I manage and maintain several projects geared towards bridging the gap between Dev and Ops with simple user interfaces and actionable data visualization.

### **Recent Projects**

#### **Kubernetes at eBay (late 2015)**

I contribute internally to eBay's Kubernetes implementation, adapting the open source <u>Kubernetes</u>

<u>Dashboard</u> to suit eBay's application lifecycle needs. I have designed and built several extensions to the

dashboard frontend code using Angular, including showing performance graphs built with D3.js, and building a search function integrated with eBay's Docker container registry.

Tools used: Docker, Kubernetes, AngularJS 1.4, Angular UI, Angular Material, ES 2015, Babel, Gulp, Sass, D3.js, Node.JS, ExpressJS

# Cloud Infrastructure Configuration Management DB Browser (mid 2015 - late 2015)

I designed and developed a web interface to browse and search the Graph Database containing configuration data objects for VMs, Applications, Tenants, Servers, etc. for eBay's Openstack deployment. I built fully interactive visualizations for browsing relationships between objects using D3 and Angular. *Tools used: D3.js, AngularJS 1.2, Bootstrap* 

## **Cloud Metrics Dashboard (early 2015)**

I designed and built a user-customizable metrics dashboard similar to Kibana for displaying metrics coming from various internal tools on a dashboard. I developed user-customizable data visualization widgets in D3 and Angular. Designed to run in fullscreen, these dashboards are displayed on TVs and projectors in the office and Network Operations Center.

Tools used: D3.js, Bootstrap, AngularJS 1.2

# Cloud Engineering Intern — eBay (June 2013 - September 2013)

I developed & supported several features for a monitoring tool for eBay's OpenStack Cloud. I built visualizations for several pages using jQuery and the Highcharts graphing library. Tools used: jQuery, Java 7, Play Framework 1.2

## Operations laaS Intern — eBay (June 2012 - September 2012)

I developed a REST API in Java for a internal VM Provisioning & Remediation tool. *Tools used: Java 7, Spring Framework* 

# **Outside Projects**

**Code Names App** (<u>Github</u>) — I built my favorite board game as a mobile friendly web application to play on the go. The idea was to be able to play while I was at the <u>PAX</u> expo hall, where there is usually little to no cell service. I designed the app to run on two phones, with no backend needed for multiplayer. I have hosted the game on my website, <u>codegoblins.com</u>. Ask me about the board encoding!

Tools used: Angular JS, Angular UI, Sass, Gulp, Bower, Webpack, Babel

**Web Project Starter Code** (<u>Github</u>) — A collection of frameworks I have been using recently for starting web projects. Includes Gulp tasks for building Sass & ES2015 code, as well as watching the source files for automatic browser reloading with Browsersync.

Tools used: AngularJS, Angular UI, Sass, Gulp, Bower, Browsersync, Webpack, Babel

**Wheel of Fortune Webapp** (*currently unpublished*) — To teach myself React and Two.JS, I am building a wheel of fortune web application to showcase some shower thoughts I had about how Als would play wheel of fortune. Ask me about some of the strategies I came up with! *Tools used: React, Sass, Gulp, Bower, Browsersync, Webpack, Babel* 

#### Education

University of California Santa Cruz — Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science